A universe without boundaries needs heroes without limits.
Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets is a adventure,
science fiction, action film directed by Luc Besson.
In the 28th century, Valerian and Laureline are special operatives
charged with keeping order throughout the human territories.
On assignment from the Minister of Defense, the two undertake a mission to Alpha, an ever-expanding metropolis where
species from across the universe have converged over centuries to share knowledge, intelligence, and cultures.
At the center of Alpha is a mysterious dark force which threatens the peaceful existence of the City of a Thousand Planets, and
Valerian and Laureline must race to identify the menace and safeguard not just Alpha, but the future of the universe.
Valerian, played by Dane DeHaan.
Laureline, played by Cara Delevingne.
Commander Arün Filitt, played by Clive Owen.
Bubble, played by Rihanna.
Jolly the Pimp, played by Ethan Hawke.
Defence Minister, played by Herbie Hancock.
Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets (French: Valérian et la Cité des mille planètes) is a 2017 space
opera film written and directed by Luc Besson, and produced by his wife, Virginie Besson-Silla.
It is based on the French science fiction comics series Valérian and Laureline, written by
Pierre Christin, illustrated by Jean-Claude Mézières, and published by Dargaud.
It stars Dane DeHaan and Cara Delevingne as Valerian and Laureline, respectively, with Clive Owen,
Rihanna, Ethan Hawke, Herbie Hancock, Kris Wu and Rutger Hauer in supporting roles.
Besson independently financed and personally funded the film.
With a production budget of around $180 million, it is both the most expensive
European and the most expensive independent film ever made.
The film is a large international co-production between France, the United
States, China, Germany, Belgium, and the United Arab Emirates.
In the film, two operatives of the United Human Federation are on a mission to
Alpha, a city inhabited by thousands of species from different planets.
Their latest mission is to uncover a destructive force beneath the sprawling city,
realizing it threatens not just Alpha, but the entire universe.
Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets was released on 20 July 2017 in Germany by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures under the Buena Vista International imprint, in the United States on 21 July by
STXfilms, in France on 26 July by EuropaCorp Distribution, in China on 25 August by China Film Group, in Belgium on 26 August by Belga Films, and 27 November in United Arab Emirates by Gulf Film.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who criticised the plot
and some of the casting, but praised the visuals.
It grossed $226 million worldwide, but due to its high production and advertising costs,
was considered a box-office bomb following its release in the United States.
The film explores themes of future, shapeshifting,
space travel, utopia, based on comic.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.